MUNFFBUR RAHMAN.M

Senior Software Engineer

Summary

Exercise knowledge of IT concepts, strategies, and methodologies for over **6.8 years** in web application and product development. Sound knowledge on web based application, utilizing web services, client-server techniques, architecture, design and development tools and technical standards.

Work Experience

SPIRIT – Logistics

May 2018 to Present

Description: To create, manage and track inbound shipments from EU origin to serving worldwide.

Roles and responsibilities

- Designed and developed front end architecture and carried out development activity under S.O.L.I.D principles.
- Developed shared utility services which are consumed by other components, hence avoiding duplication or repetition of code.
- Upgraded core business functionality in more advanced way, engaging more user interaction, as the advance one is best in UX and efficient in performance.
- Implemented language translation for different European countries.
- Involved in code review, refactoring and configuring CI / CD in Jenkins for various environments by integrating SonarQube with defined coding standards and triggering build after code review and unit testing is more than 95%.
- Developed fail proof content spoofing product.

Accomplishments

• Received summit award for resuming application back from red to green zone and later released for production.

Dealer Management System - Automobile

Oct 2017 to May 2018

Description: To manage, track all two wheeler related business throughout India, such as vehicle in stock, service and sales from dealers associated with company.

Roles and responsibilities

- Being a full stack developer, analyzing business requirements and implementing with adherence to best industry coding practices and design pattern.
- Segregation of components into shared, child and generic, resulting in creation of fewer components and maintaining existing code base robust and modular.
- Developed REST API using Express.js with middleware of JWT authentication.

Accomplishments

• Refactored application which resulted in reduction of size to 60% leading to fast loading and efficient in terms of performance.

Slingshot - Document Administration

Jun 2016 to Sep 2017

Description: Microsoft office add-on, used to manage, assign and track progress of users on shared word document content assigned by the document owner.

Roles and responsibilities

- Converted complex user interface to ease with minimum view port availability.
- Codes written in component are singleton in nature which is solely responsible for defined business operation, making scalable compliance.

Contact

⊠muneeb.rahman.m@gmail.com

(+91 95667 47746

Employment

Mphasis Limited Bangalore

Senior Software

Engineer May 18 to Present

KasponTechworks

Chennai

Pvt Ltd

Senior Software

Engineer Jul 15 to May 18

Qnex Technologies

Chennai

Team Leader Mar 14 to Jun 15

Skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript and Typescript

Web Technologies

REST, HTML5, CSS3 and SCSS

Data Modelling

JSON, JSONP, XML and CSV

Libraries/APIs

HighCharts.js, sheet xlsx-js, jQuery, Angular Material, ng-bootstrap and Node.js.

Tools

GitLab, Git, Postman, Tortoise SVN, Jenkins, WinSCP and Visual Studio Code.

Paradigms

Agile, SAFe and Scrum

Platforms

Windows and Ubuntu

Frameworks

Bootstrap, Express.js, Vue, Jasmine karma, Jest and Angular 4 & 8

Mis

User Experience (UX), Responsive Web Design (RWD)

Application Protocol

LDAP

Data Management

MySQL and MongoDB

MUNFFBUR RAHMAN.M

Senior Software Engineer

Vendor Training portal (UK) – Electronics

Feb 2016 to Jun 2016

Description: To promote, give training on handling latest desktop, laptop and other electronic gadgets for vendor, post which they are capable to address customer.

Roles and responsibilities

- Design and developed algorithm for quiz on specific product based on vendor location which notifies vendor to take quiz before a new product is launched
- Developed customized reports on vendor business operations and activities, increasing productivity and revenue for the organization.

Project Management System - Financial Sector

Jul 2015 to Jan 2016

Description: To create, monitor and track IT projects from different departments with respect to time and resource availability of developer.

Roles and responsibilities

- Developed dashboard by rendering various charts (pie, bar, column) for different departments. Application is more of monitoring in nature, resulting in more pictorial and less textual representation.
- Developed and implemented resource availability algorithm from scratch.
- Exporting charts in various formats such as PDF, PNG and JPEG and reports in excel format.

Accomplishments

• Created universal login module which is consumed by other projects for both internal and external (vendor) users.

Resource Management Portal – Telecom Sector

Sep 2014 to Jun 2015

Description: To create, track associate and automate mobile number screening on portal, to ease business operations.

Roles and responsibilities

- Developed algorithm based on mobile number which has not attended by any associate and assigning it to available associate. After completion of business operation, the request is flagged and forwarded for further process.
- Tracking associate details, like number of hour's clocked, customer attended and targets achieved out of target assigned and finally emailing their report sheet to managers.

Accomplishments

- Fetching automated mobile number instead of manual resulted in decrease of process time and increase in production.
- Automated report sheet of associate saved manager time in creating it manually which saved time and resource.

Dynamic and static websites

Mar 2014 to Aug 2014

- Worked on multiple frontend and backend components independently.
- Developed dining table reservation algorithm from scratch and incorporated it.
- Created ecommerce website from scratch and integrated payment gateway.

Education

MCA – Master of computer application Veltech Multitech Dr Rangarajan Dr Sakunthala Engineering College, Avadi – Chennai.

Portfolio

https://www.hackerrank.com/mune eb_rahman

The https://muneeb-rahman-m.github.io/portfolio/

Description

Webpage contains game named as **Space Shooters** under **Apps** menu which is present in android mobile look a-like design. User needs to unlock the web mobile using mouse by click and

drag the lock icon in screen towards right until it overlaps with unlock icon. Once overlapped, it's unlocked. Click menu located in bottom right of the mobile screen.

Click game icon in screen then click on play button. Voila! Game has started. Game is played using **keyboard**. Enjoy!!... ③

Personal Details

Date of birth : 12-Sep-1988

Gender : Male

Nationality : Indian

Languages : English, Urdu and

Tamil

Marital status : Married

Awards

Monthly Summit award

Appreciation for exemplary commitment and collaboration with team to complete sprint deliverable's consistently.